In this video we're going to start our discussion of garbage collection or
在本视频中，我们将开始讨论垃圾收集或
automatic memory management. This will take us a few videos to get through and
自动内存管理。这需要我们看几个视频才能看完
this first video is just an overview of the problem. And then we'll talk about
第一个视频只是问题的概述。然后我们再谈一谈
specific techniques in subsequent videos. To set the stage, let's first talk about
具体技巧将在后续视频中介绍。作为铺垫，我们先来谈一谈
the problem that we're trying to solve. So, if one has to manage memory manually,
我们试图解决的问题。因此，如果必须手动管理内存，
meaning you have to do all the allocation and deallocation explicitly yourself, that
这意味着你必须自己明确地做所有的分配和取消分配，
is a hard way to programming leads to certain kinds of bugs that are very
是一种很难编程的方法，会导致某些类型的错误，这些错误非常
difficult to eliminate from programs. So, in particular, these days you see this
很难从节目中消除。所以，特别是这几天，你会看到这个
primarily in C and C++ programs. Those are the main languages that are used that have
主要是在C和C++程序中。这些是使用的主要语言，具有
manual memory management. And, the kinds of storage bugs that you can get because
手动内存管理。而且，您可以得到的存储错误种类是因为
it has manual memory management are things like forgetting to free unused memory so
它有手动内存管理功能，比如忘记释放未使用的内存，因此
that's a, it means a memory leak. Dereferencing dangling pointers,
那是一个，意思是内存泄露。取消引用悬挂指针，
overriding parts of a data structure, unintentionally. And actually there's a
无意中重写数据结构的各部分。实际上有一个
few more things, although these are probably the three most common problems
虽然这可能是最常见的三个问题
that people have and these bugs are really hard to find. And I want to emphasize that
这些细菌真的很难找到。我想强调的是
these kinds of bugs are often some of the very, very last bugs to be found in, in
这些类型的错误通常是一些非常、非常晚才能发现的错误。
complex systems. They often persist into production and sometimes for a very long
复杂的系统。他们经常坚持生产，有时会坚持很长时间。
time after the code is in production use. And why is that? The reason is that these,
代码投入生产使用后的时间。为什么会这样呢？原因是这些，
these kinds of bugs, storage bugs, typically have effects that are far away
这些类型的错误，存储错误，通常会产生很远的影响
in time and space from the source and so how can that happen? Well let's think
在时间和空间上，从源头开始，那么这是怎么发生的呢？好吧，让我们想一想
about some object in memory and now let's say only on interesting you might have
关于内存中的某个对象，现在让我们只说有趣的，你可能会有
some fields, let's say you have a few fields and I am keeping some pointers to
一些字段，假设您有几个字段，我保留了一些指向
it. So somewhere on program is a reference to this particular object and now I come
它。所以程序中的某个地方引用了这个特定的对象，现在我来了
along and free it. So I am doing my own memory management like free this object
一起去解救它。所以我正在进行我自己的内存管理，比如释放这个对象
but I forget that I had this pointer. And so now what's happen all the storage has
但是我忘了我有这个指针。所以现在发生的事情是所有的存储都有
been freed it's no longer really valid memory but the pointer still exist to it.
被释放，它不再是真正有效的内存，但是指向它的指针仍然存在。
And then when I come along and allocate something else it might allocate the same
然后，当我出现并分配其他东西时，它可能会分配相同的东西
piece of memory. So this might now be a different kind of object, okay. So I might
一段记忆。所以现在这可能是一种不同的物体，好的。所以我可能会
have a different type here even. In this memory might be used for something
甚至在这里也有不同的类型。在这个记忆中可能被用来做某事
completely different and now I have a pointer that says it thinks it's a red
完全不同，现在我有一个指针，说它认为它是红色的
object, it's pointing to a blue object. And when I come in and write stuff into
对象，它指向一个蓝色对象。当我进来把东西写进
this object, of course I'm just writing nonsense. So I, this, whatever piece of
这个物体，当然我只是在写无稽之谈。所以我，这个，不管是什么
code holds this pointer thinks it's still the old kind of object. It will write some
持有该指针的代码认为它仍然是旧类型的对象。它会写一些
bits in here and when I go in some other part of the program possibly quite far
比特在这里，当我进入程序的其他部分时，可能会很远
away go out and read out, this is a blue object, I'll just get some random garbage
出去读出，这是一个蓝色的物体，我会随便拿一些垃圾
and that will probably cause my program to cash. So this is a very, very old problem.
这可能会导致我的计划兑现。所以这是一个非常、非常古老的问题。
It's been studied since at least the 1950s. It was first thought about
至少从20世纪50年代开始，人们就开始对它进行研究。这是我们最初想到的
carefully in list. And there are some well-known techniques for completely
仔细地列在单子上。有一些众所周知的技术可以完全
automatic memory management so you don't have to manage memory yourself. And this
自动内存管理，因此您不必自己管理内存。还有这个
only became mainstream actually in the 1990s so with the popularity of Java.
实际上直到20世纪90年代才成为主流，所以随着Java的流行。
Prior to that time there was really no mainstream language that used automatic
在此之前，确实没有使用自动语言的主流语言
memory managements so that's really just in the last now almost twenty years that
内存管理，所以这实际上只是在过去的近20年里，
garbage collection and automatic memory management in general became a popular
垃圾收集和自动内存管理通常变得流行起来
mainstream programming technique. So the basic strategy in automatic memory
主流编程技术。所以自动记忆的基本策略
management is, is pretty simple. So, when an object is created, when we allocate a
管理是，是很简单的。因此，当创建对象时，当我们分配
new object the system, the run time system will find some unused space for that
新对象在系统中，运行时系统将为该对象找到一些未使用的空间
object and it will just allocate it. So whenever you say new of some class name in
对象，它将只分配它。所以，每当您说到某个类名的新名称时
Cool. Some memory is automatically allocated by the system, some previously
凉爽的。有些内存是由系统自动分配的，有些是以前分配的
unused memory is automatically allocated by the system for that object. And if you
系统会自动为该对象分配未使用的内存。如果你
keep doing this over and over and over again and after awhile you're going to run
一遍又一遍地这样做，过一段时间你就会跑了
out of space. So eventually there is no more unused space left for additional obj
空间不够。因此，最终没有更多未使用的空间可供其他对象使用
ects. And at that point you have to do something. You have to reclaim some of the
等。在这一点上，你必须做点什么。你必须回收一些
space in order to allocate more objects and the observation that garbage
空间为了分配更多的对象而观察到垃圾
collection systems rely upon is that some of the spaces being used is probably
收集系统所依赖的是一些正在使用的空间可能
occupied by objects that will never be used again. So they, some of these objects
被永远不会再使用的物品占据。所以他们，这些物体中的一些
are not going to be referred to again by the program and if we can figure out which
不会被程序再次引用，如果我们能找出
objects those are, which objects are not longer going to be used. Then we could
那些对象，哪些对象将不再被使用。那我们就可以
deallocate them and reuse the space for new objects. So the big question is, how
取消分配它们，并将空间重新用于新对象。所以最大的问题是，如何
can we know that an object will never be used again? And, most of the garbage
我们能知道一件物品永远不会再被使用吗？而且，大多数垃圾
collection techniques that are out there today rely on the following observation,
今天存在的收集技术依赖于下面的观察，
then that's that a program can only use the objects that it can find and what do
这就是说，程序只能使用它能找到的对象以及它能做什么
we mean by that? So I'm going to switch colors so let's take a look at this piece
我们的意思是这样吗？所以我要换颜色，让我们来看看这件作品
of code so what's going to happen? Well when we execute this the first thing that
那么会发生什么呢？嗯，当我们执行这项工作时，首先要做的就是
happens is we allocate an A object, alright. And it's assigned x, so x will
就是我们分配一个A对象，好吧。它被赋值为x，所以x将
have a pointer to that object. And then, in the body of this let, what's going to
具有指向该对象的指针。然后，在这封信的正文中，
happen well, we're going to assign x, the value that y points to so y is another
发生的很好，我们将赋值x，y指向的值，所以y是另一个
variable. It points to some other objects in memory, okay. And what's going to
变量。它指向内存中的其他对象，好的。那么接下来会发生什么呢？
happen, when we execute this assignment is that we're going to remove the old value
当我们执行此赋值时发生的情况是，我们将删除旧值
of x and x now is going to point to this object. Now observe that this object a is
会指向这个物体。现在观察到这个对象a是
unreachable. Meaning it has no references to it. There are no longer any pointers to
遥不可及。意思是它没有提到它。不再有任何指向
it. And how do I know that? Well, a brand new here when it was created. I only
它。我怎么知道的？嗯，这里刚造出来的时候是全新的。只有我
created one pointer to it, x and then I immediately assigned x to something else.
创建了一个指向它的指针，x，然后我立即将x赋给了其他东西。
So I dropped the only pointer to A. There is no reference to A anywhere in the
所以我删除了指向A的唯一指针。
program. And so the program will never be able to find it again. The program, if no
程序。所以程序再也找不到它了。程序，如果没有
variable or data structure in the program has a pointer to A, then A can never be
程序中的变量或数据结构有指向A的指针，则A永远不能
referred to by the program in the future. So any kind of subsequent execution of the
在未来的程序中引用。因此任何类型的后续执行
program has no p ointers to A and therefore it will never use A again and so
程序没有指向A的指针，因此它再也不会使用A了
the space ray can be reclaimed and used for another object. Now it turns out that
空间射线可以回收并用于另一个对象。现在事实证明，
we need a more general definition of object reachability than this example
我们需要比本例更一般的对象可达性定义
illustrates so let's take a look at that. We're going to say that an object x is
图解，让我们来看看这个。我们要说物体x是
reachable if and only if one of the following two things is true. So either A
仅当且仅当以下两件事之一为真时才可达。所以要么是A
register contains a pointer to x. So either the x is reachable immediately from
寄存器包含指向x的指针。因此可以立即从
some register. Remember that the registers contain things like the local variables in
有些人注册了。请记住，寄存器包含类似于
there and the intermediate expressions and they're just you know, the values that the
还有中间表达式，它们就是你知道的，
program has immediate access to or another reachable object y contains a pointer to
程序可以立即访问或另一个可访问对象y包含指向
x. And so what does this say? Well, this says you're going start at the register so
那么这上面写的是什么呢？嗯，这上面说你要从收银台开始
you know the program might be implemented using a few registers. And then you're
您知道，该程序可能使用几个寄存器来实现。然后你就会
going to look at all the things that those registers point to, all the objects that
我们来看看这些寄存器所指向的所有东西，所有
they point to. And you will look at the pointers in those objects and everything
他们指着。您将查看这些对象中的指针和所有内容
they can point to, okay. And some of these things might overlap. I mean, some of
他们可以指出来，好的。其中一些东西可能会重叠。我是说，有些人
these there might be multiple things which are reachable by more than one path
这些可能存在多个可通过多条路径到达的事物
starting at the registers. But the complete side of things that you can
从收银台开始。但是你所能做的事情的完整的一面
reach, beginning at the registers and following all the possible pointers, those
从寄存器开始，跟随所有可能的指针，到达那些
are all the reachable objects. And then the complement of that set, an unreachable
是所有可到达的对象。然后是那个集合的补码，一个无法到达的
object is one that isn't reachable. So all the other objects, the ones that you were
对象是无法到达的对象。所以所有其他的物体，那些你曾经是的物体
not able to reach by recursively starting at registers and following pointers as far
不能通过递归地从寄存器开始并跟随指针到达
as you could, those objects can never be used. Because clearly the implementation
正如您所能做到的，这些对象永远不能使用。因为很明显，实现
can only access things through registers and, and then only find additional things
只能通过寄存器和访问内容，然后只能查找其他内容
by, you know loading pointers out of objects that it could reach from the
通过，您可以知道从对象中加载指针可以从
registers. So anything that it can reach by some sequence of sub-steps will never
寄存器。因此，它可以通过某些子步骤序列到达的任何东西都永远不会
be used again, and is garbage. So let's take a look at another example that
再用一次，就是垃圾。那么我们来看另一个例子，
illustrates some interesting aspects of re achability and its use in automatic memory
说明了可达性的一些有趣方面及其在自动记忆中的用法
management. So what does this example do? The first thing it does, it allocates an A
管理层。那么这个示例做了什么呢？它做的第一件事就是分配一个A
object, on the heap and assigns that to the variable x. So, x is a pointer to that
对象，并将其赋给变量x。因此，x是指向该对象的指针
object. And then it allocates a B object and y will point to that object. And then,
对象。然后它分配一个B对象，y将指向该对象。然后,
it assigns the value of y to x, alright. So, we'll have this configuration and, and
它将y的值赋给x，好的。因此，我们将使用此配置，并且
now let's draw a line here, okay and we'll come back and let's remember this point in
现在让我们在这里画一条线，好的，我们会回来的，让我们记住这一点
time, what things look like at this point in time. And then we're going to go off
时间，这个时间点上的情况。然后我们要出发了
and we're going to execute this conditional. And notice that this
我们要执行这个有条件的。请注意这一点
conditional is going to do. It's going to always be true, alright? So the predicate
有条件的就行了。这将永远是事实，好吗？所以谓词
will always be true so it'll never take the false branch. All it's going to ever
将永远是真的，所以它永远不会走上错误的枝条。它所要做的就是
do is take the true branch and what's it going to do there, is immediately going to
取真正的分支，它将在那里做什么，立即
overwrite x. And so x is going to wind up pointing at some other new object. It
重写x，所以x最终会指向其他一些新的物体。它
doesn't matter what it is. And now, let's say that at this point right here, is
不管是什么都无关紧要。现在，让我们假设在这一点上，
where we try to do a garbage collection. So you know, for some reason this is the
在那里我们尝试进行垃圾收集。所以你知道，出于某种原因，这是
point where the program stops and tries to collect unused memory. And what can it
程序停止并尝试收集未使用内存的位置。它能做什么呢？
collect? Well, just like before cuz the example up to this point is essentially
对方付费吗？嗯，就像以前一样，因为到现在为止的例子基本上是
the same. We can see that this object is unreachable, okay. So the first A object
一样的。我们可以看到这个物体是无法到达的，好的。所以第一个A对象
becomes unreachable at that point and it can be collected. Now what about the
在这一点上变得无法到达，并且它可以被收集。现在我们来看一下
second object? Well it is reachable, it's clearly reachable. It's reachable through
第二件物品呢？嗯，它是可以到达的，它显然是可以到达的。它可以通过以下途径到达
x, okay at that point and it's also reachable as it happens through y. And so
好的，在这一点上，它也是可以到达的，因为它发生在y上，所以
it's not garbage and it's not going to be collected but notice that the x value is
它不是垃圾，也不会被收集，但请注意，x值是
always going to be overwritten, okay? So the program, the compiler doesn't know
总是会被覆盖的，好吗？所以程序，编译器不知道
that this branch is always going to be true. So, it doesn't realize that the
这个分支将永远是正确的。所以，它没有意识到
value that x has at this point won't ever be used again but that value is
此时x拥有的值将不会再被使用，但该值
immediately going to be overwritten, every time we take this conditional. And
马上就会被覆盖，每次我们接受这个条件。和
furthermore, if y is not used any place else in the program, if y i s dead at this
此外，如果y没有在程序中的任何其他位置使用，如果y已经死在这一点上。
point. Let's say that y is dead here. Then, neither one of these references to B
重点。假设y在这里是死的。那么，这些对B的引用都不是
is ever gonna be touched again. So in fact the B value will never be used again even
再也不会被碰了。所以事实上，B值甚至不会再被使用
though it is reachable. And so what this tells you is that reachability is an
虽然它是可以触手可及的。所以这告诉你可达性是一种
approximation. And by that I mean it's an approximation for the objects that will
近似值。我的意思是这是物体的近似值
never be used again. What we're really interested in when we do garbage
再也不能用了。我们做垃圾时真正感兴趣的是什么
collection is collecting objects that will never be used in the future execution of
集合是收集在将来的执行中永远不会使用的对象
the program. Because obviously that space is wasted and could be put to some other
这个项目。因为很明显，这个空间是浪费的，可以放到其他地方去
use that might be better and reachability approximates that. So if an object is
使用可能更好的，可达性接近于此。因此，如果一个对象是
unreachable it definitely won't be used again however, just because an object is
但是，它肯定不会再被使用，只是因为一个对象
reachable it's not a guarantee that it will be used again. So now let's talk
但不能保证它会被再次使用。所以现在让我们谈谈
about how we do garbage collection in Coolc. So Coolc has a fairly simple
关于我们如何在Coolc进行垃圾收集。所以Coolc有一个相当简单的
structure. It uses an accumulator in which of course points to an object and that
结构。它使用累加器，在累加器中当然指向对象，并且
object may point to other objects and so on. So we have to trace all the objects
对象可以指向其他对象，依此类推。所以我们必须追踪所有的物体
reachable from the accumulator but we also have to worry about the stack pointer so
可从累加器访问，但我们还必须担心堆栈指针，因此
there's also stuff reachable from the stack. And each stack frame of course may
还有一些东西可以从堆栈中拿到。当然，每个堆栈帧可以
contain pointers like, and you know for example the method parameters that are
包含指针，例如，您知道的方法参数是
stored on the stack. Each stack frame may also contain some non-pointers, alright?
存储在堆栈上。每个堆栈帧也可能包含一些非指针，对吗？
So if I think about the layout of each activation record there would be some mix
因此，如果我考虑一下每个激活记录的布局，会有一些混合
of pointers and non-pointers. Things like the return address so we have to know the
指针和非指针。像寄信人地址这样的东西，所以我们必须知道
layout of the frame. But if we do know the layout and of course the compiler is
框架的布局。但是如果我们知道布局，当然编译器是
deciding on the layout so it naturally does know the layout, it can find all the
决定布局因此它自然知道布局，它可以找到所有
pointers in the frame. Essentially, the compiler has to keep a record for each
框架中的指针。从本质上讲，编译器必须为每个
kind of activation record it builds for each methods. If activation record for a
它为每个方法构建的激活记录的种类。如果激活记录用于
method foo and let's say that activation record has four slots then the compiler
方法foo，假设激活记录有四个槽，那么编译器
would need to keep track of which one of these were pointers to objects. And
需要跟踪其中哪一个是指向对象的指针。和
perhaps the second , and the fourth element of the frame are always pointers
也许框架的第二个和第四个元素始终是指针
to objects and the other two are always non-pointers. So the somewhere, the
指向对象，另外两个始终是非指针。所以在某个地方，那个
compiler has to keep track of this information so that the garbage collector
编译器必须跟踪此信息，以便垃圾回收器
will know at Run time when it's looking at an activation record for foo where the
在运行时，当它查看foo的激活记录时，将知道
pointers that it needs to follow are. So in Coolc, we start tracing from the
它需要遵循的指针是。因此，在Coolc中，我们从
accumulator and the stack and these are called the roots, okay. So, in garbage
累加器和堆栈，这些叫做根，好的。所以，在垃圾里
collection terminology the roots are the registers from which you begin tracing out
集合术语根是您开始跟踪的寄存器
all the reachable objects. And if we do that here, what we can do, so you see we
所有可访问的对象。如果我们在这里做到这一点，我们能做的就是，所以你可以看到我们
have our object, here we have our accumulator, excuse me and our stack
有我们的对象，这里有我们的累加器，对不起，还有我们的堆栈
pointer and so we can just walk through. This little diagram of memory and find all
指针，这样我们就可以走过去了。这张记忆的小图表，找到所有
the reachable objects so the acummulator points to object A so we'll mark that as
可达对象，因此累加器指向对象A，因此我们将其标记为
reachable. And A points to C so we'll mark it as reachable. C points to E so we'll
可以到达。A指向C，因此我们将其标记为可达。C指向E，所以我们将
mark E as reachable. The stack pointer has a couple of frames on it. The first frame
将E标记为可达。堆栈指针上有几个帧。第一帧
has no pointers. The second frame points to E. We've already touched that one. It's
没有指针。第二帧指向E，我们已经摸过那一帧了。它是
already marked so we can mark it again but it doesn't matter as long as it gets
已经标记好了，所以我们可以再标记一次，但只要它
marked by somebody and now everything that is not marked is unreachable. So what
被某人标记了，现在所有没有标记的东西都是无法到达的。那又怎样
objects didn't we touch and are traversal of the reachable objects? Well those are
我们没有接触的对象，并且正在遍历可到达的对象吗？嗯，这些都是
objects B and D. And so those are, unreachable objects and they can be
对象B和D，这些是无法到达的对象，它们可以
reclaimed and we can reuse their storage. Now, one interesting thing to note here is
回收，我们就可以重复利用它们的储藏。现在，这里需要注意的一件有趣的事情是
that, just because an object has pointers to it, it does not mean it is reachable,
那就是，仅仅因为一个对象有指向它的指针，并不意味着它是可到达的，
so notice here object D. Object D actually has a pointer to it, okay and yet object D
所以请注意这里的对象D。对象D实际上有一个指向它的指针，好的，但是对象D
is unreachable and why is that? Well because the only pointers to it are from
是遥不可及的吗？为什么呢？嗯，因为指向它的唯一指针来自于
other unreachable objects. So it's important here to, you know just
其他无法触及的对象。所以在这里很重要的是，你知道
understand that it's not the case that every unreachable object has no pointers
请理解，并不是每个无法到达的对象都没有指针
to it. There will be some unreachable objects or there may be some unreachable
为它干杯。将存在一些无法访问的对象，或者可能存在一些无法访问的对象
objects that actually do have pointers to it, to them but they will on ly come from
实际上确实有指向它的指针的对象，但它们只能来自
other unreachable objects. So every garbage collection scheme has the
其他无法触及的对象。因此，每个垃圾收集方案都有
following steps. We're going to allocate space as needed for new objects, so we
以下步骤。我们将根据需要为新对象分配空间，因此我们
just go ahead and allocate new space as long as we have space, so whenever we need
只要我们有空间，就继续分配新的空间，所以无论何时我们需要
it. And when space runs out we need to compute what objects might be used again.
它。当空间耗尽时，我们需要计算哪些对象可能会再次被使用。
And generally that's done by tracing objects reachable from a set of root
通常，这是通过跟踪可从一组根目录访问的对象来实现的
registers and then we're going to free the complement of that set. We're going to
寄存器，然后我们将释放该集合的补码。我们要去
free the space used by the objects not found in part A. And I want to say that
释放A部分中未找到的对象使用的空间，我想说的是
some strategies do perform garbage collection before the space actually runs
有些策略确实会在空间实际运行之前执行垃圾收集
out and we'll actually look at one of those in a future video.
我们将在未来的视频中看到其中的一个。